## Stephen Boyer

Fort Collins, CO (970) 689-1813

sboyer307@gmail.com; www.stephenboyer.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/steve-boyer

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

An ambitious and results-driven Java Software Engineer with experience from the IT and services sectors. Pays meticulous attention to detail, uses excellent knowledge of Java, MySQL, JavaScript, and HTML, and delivers projects on time and within budget. Applies an analytical approach to solving problems, communicates effectively at all levels, and collaborates effectively in team settings. Committed to continuing professional development.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Currently seeking a challenging new Full-Stack Software Engineer position (Java) that will fully utilize the existing knowledge and experience and provide opportunities for further personal and professional development.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Software Engineering

Full-Stack Design

SDLC, Agile

Project Management

Web Development

Relational Databases

REST API Design

Middleware Technologies

Data Storage

Stakeholder Engagement

Cross-Functional Collaboration

Programming & Testing

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY**

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, OS X

Languages: Java, C++, C#

Web/Scripting: JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, Python, Linux Shell (bash)

Middleware: JPA, Hibernate, JDBC, Spring MVC

Other: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Maven, Git, SVN, Microsoft Office

### CAREER SUMMARY

#### Language I/O, LLC, Cheyenne, WY (May 2015 - Oct 2016)

Language I/O provides a multilingual translation service through LinguistNow, which provides the tools to automate human or machine translation through a Java server application.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs
- · Identified and suggested new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team productivity
- Worked in an Agile Development Team and used technologies such as Glassfish server, MySQL, J2EE, JPA, JSP, and JavaScript to maintain and enhance an enterprise Java application
- Designed, maintained, and implemented REST APIs
- Stored new data using Java persistence libraries and MySQL, and used jQuery to develop asynchronous web pages
- Streamlined deployment process by developing continuous integration tools
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches

## Cheyenne Technology, LLC, Cheyenne, WY (Apr 2013 - Aug 2014)

Cheyenne Technology, LLC develops websites that leverage social media channels and support mobile devices. The company designs PHP-based web pages for a variety of local clients, and uses the Concrete5 CMS.

#### **Software Development Intern**

 Completed website updates (remotely) for various clients and resolved numerous problems in Java support software

#### OTHER EXPERIENCE

Ark Regional Services, Laramie, WY (May 2012 - Aug 2013)

# Direct Support Staff University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY (July 2011 - May 2012) **Resident Assistant**

## **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, University of Wyoming, Laramie, WY, May 2015 Trustee's Pride Scholarship, Hathaway Honors Scholarship, May 2009 May 2013 Associated Students of the University of Wyoming (Student Senate), National Society of Collegiate Scholars